在monadic图像处理中，我们采用输入图像，并将功能应用于每一个
In monadic image processing we take an input image and we apply a function to every single
该图像中的像素。函数的结果应用于特定的
pixel in that image. The result of the function applied to a particular
输入图像中的像素被分配给输出图像中的相应像素，并且
pixel in the input image is assigned to the corresponding pixel in the output image, and
我们对图像中的每个像素使用相同的函数。
we use the same function for every pixel within the image.
让我们来看看这个低分辨率的例子，以了解它在实践中是如何工作的。
Let’s have a look at this low-resolution example to get an idea of how it works in practice.
所以我们有一个函数，我们将其应用于
So we have a function, which we apply to the
第一个像素输入图像，并将结果分配给输出中的第一个像素
first pixel input image, and the result is assigned to the first pixel in the output
图片。然后我们为第二个像素和第三个像素做同样的事情，依此类推，
image. And then we do the same thing for the second pixel and the third pixel and so on,
直到我们处理了图像中的每个像素。
until we have processed every single pixel within the image.
现在这里的演示是连续的;我们将它应用于一个接一个的像素。
Now the demonstration here is sequential; we have applied it to one pixel after another.
如果计算机具有显着的并行处理能力，则可以应用该功能
If the computer has significant parallel processing power then it is possible to apply the function
并行的所有像素。
to all of the pixels in parallel.
那么我们使用的函数f（x）是什么呢？
So what is this function f(x) that we used
在前面的例子中？那么我们可以使用许多非常有用的功能。
in the previous example? Well there are lots of really useful functions that we could use.
第一个也许是我们可以取输入像素的平方根。
The first is, perhaps, we could take the square root of the input pixel.
我们可以做的另一件事是改变输入像素的类型。也许我们可以转换
Another thing we could do is change the type of the input pixel. Perhaps we could convert
无符号整数像素为双像素，反之亦然。
unsigned integer pixels into double pixels or vice versa.
也许我们可以通过对每个图像进行操作来改变图像的亮度或对比度
Maybe we could change the brightness or the contrast of the image by operating on each
像素单独。我们可以执行一个名为直方图的功能
pixel individually. We could perform a function called histogram
归一化，我们将在下一节中讨论这个问题。
normalisation, and we will talk about that in a following section.
我们可以执行一个名为thresholding的操作，我们也将在即将到来的时候讨论
We could perform an operation called thresholding, which we will also talk about in upcoming
部分。我们可以进行艺术性的转型
section. And we could perform an arty kind of transformation
我们将在很短的时间内再次讨论这个问题。
called posterization, and again we will talk about that very shortly.